

□+1 613 795 4472 | **☑** yo@micmax.pw | **☆** www.micmax.pw | **□** mic-max | **□** micmax

## Summary \_\_\_\_

Current Senior at Carleton with an expected graduation date in April 2019. 5+ years of programming experience, with a focus in backend development and software engineering. In between schoolwork I like attending hackathons and exploring hobbyist electronics. I'm very interested in parallel & distributed computing where performance metrics are critical. Seeking job opportunities in North America for a role I can mature into and become an effective addition to the team.

## Skills

Languages C, C++, Go, Java, Node.js, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, \( \mathbb{M}\_E \times \)

Frameworks / Libraries

JUnit, Cucumber, Mocha, Vue.js, Express, MongoDB, jQuery, socket.io, Cilk++, MPI

Development

Git, Eclipse, Jira, Agile, SCRUM, Linux, AWS, Docker, Test-driven development

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### Martello Technologies Kanata, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - SUMMER STUDENT

Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Replaced a legacy dashboard with a Vue.js application which iteracted with our Rest Api
- Developed custom Vue UI components for our MDS library (e.g. a modal, a table that can be sorted & filtered, etc.)
- · Created a suite of Mocha tests on currently supported Crud operations of containers and devices making use of equivalence partitioning
- Presented my progress at biweekly sprint meetings to the management team, shareholders, and all other developers

#### **Carleton University: School of Computer Science**

Ottawa, Canada Sept. 2016 - Present

TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Comp 1406: Introduction to Computer Science II | Comp 2406: Fundamentals of Web Applications
   Held office hours, organized and ran weekly workshops following the course content and assignments
- Marked assignments based on a correction grid all teaching assistants created

Projects\_\_\_\_\_

### **Android Application - Blitz SMS**

Ottawa, Canada

CO-LEAD DEVELOPER — CREATED FOR A 3RD YEAR SOFTWARE ENGINEERING COURSE

Sept. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- · An android application that can make requests to our multiple services and presents the data in a relevant manner
- Server makes API requests to answer the user's request and send that back using the linked twilio number
- Managed a team of four students and assigned weekly tasks, reviewed pull requests, and developed the server using a unique transfer protocol
- · Our client-server architecture made use of several design patterns such as: Singleton, Strategy, Template Method, Facade, and Retry

#### 8 Bit Breadboard CPU Ottawa, Canada

DESIGN INSPIRED BY A BEN EATER SERIES ON YOUTUBE

Sep. 2017 - Oct. 2018

- Recreated an 8 Bit CPU on a series of breadboards using mostly 74LS TTL components to develop a greater understanding of the fundamentals of how computers function. I was able to create and run very simple programs in the Turing complete system's byte code
- Goal: Scale it to 16 bits and add more ram for more complex programs and create a simple compiler for its bytecode

### Honors & Awards

2018 **NSERC Experience Award**, Martello Technologies

Kanata, Canada Ottawa, Canada

2015 Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française, DELF B1

### Education

#### Carleton University Ottawa, Canada

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE HONOURS: SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sept. 2015 - Apr. 2019

Relevant Coursework:

- Parallel Programming for Clusters & Multi-Core Processors, Design & Analysis of Algorithms
- Software Quality Assurance, Software Product Management, Object-Oriented Software Engineering
- David A. Thomas Scholarship in Computer Science for attaining a 10.0 CGPA
- Developer for cuHacking the student organized hackathon

NOVEMBER 12, 2018 MICHAEL MAXWELL · RÉSUMÉ